const question = document.querySelector('#question');
const choices = Array.from(document.querySelectorAll('.choice-text'));
const progressText = document.querySelector('#progressText');
const scoreText = document.querySelector('#score');
const progressBarFull = document.querySelector('#progressBarFull');

let currentQuestion = {};
let acceptingAnswers = true;
let score = 0;
let questionCounter = 0;
let availableQuestions = [];

let questions = [
	{
		question: 'In which country is playing "Minecraft" in school allowed?',
		choice1: 'Singapore',
		choice2: 'Malaysia',
		choice3: 'Thailand',
		choice4: 'Sweden',
		answer: 4,
	},
	{
		question:
			'Which real life animal was recorded to produce the sound effects of the Ghasts?',
		choice1: 'Cow',
		choice2: 'Cat',
		choice3: 'Dog',
		choice4: 'Sheep',
		answer: 2,
	},
	{
		question: 'When was Minecraft released?',
		choice1: '15th Jan 2009',
		choice2: '18th November 2011',
		choice3: '27th June 2004',
		choice4: '29th March 2010',
		answer: 2,
	},
	{
		question: 'Which game inspired Notch to create Mincraft?',
		choice1: 'Infiniminer',
		choice2: 'Mines of Mars',
		choice3: 'Adventure Miner',
		choice4: 'Deep Miner',
		answer: 1,
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following is NOT a Minecraft mod?',
		choice1: 'Aether',
		choice2: 'Aether II',
		choice3: 'Aether II: Reloaded',
		choice4: 'Aether II: The Silver City',
		answer: 3,
	},
	{
		question: 'How many people like to play "Minecraft" every month?',
		choice1: '100M+',
		choice2: '55M+',
		choice3: '200M+',
		choice4: '195M+',
		answer: 3,
	},
	{
		question: 'How many night creatures can you find in "Minecraft"?',
		choice1: '10',
		choice2: '3',
		choice3: '7',
		choice4: '5',
		answer: 1,
	},
	{
		question: 'How far away can you be from a Ghast for it to see you?',
		choice1: '30 blocks',
		choice2: '25 blocks',
		choice3: '100 blocks',
		choice4: '50 blocks',
		answer: 3,
	},
	{
		question: 'What is the best way to kill a Spider in Minecraft?',
		choice1: 'With a sword',
		choice2: 'With a stick',
		choice3: 'With a stick and a spider eye',
		choice4: 'With a pickaxe',
		answer: 1,
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of these mobs does not drop a item?',
		choice1: 'Horse',
		choice2: 'Donkey',
		choice3: 'Polar Beast',
		choice4: 'Silverfish',
		answer: 4,
	},
];

const SCORE_POINTS = 100;
const MAX_QUESTIONS = 10;

startGame = () => {
	questionCounter = 0;
	score = 0;
	availableQuestions = [...questions];
	getNewQuestion();
};

getNewQuestion = () => {
	if (availableQuestions.length === 0 || questionCounter > MAX_QUESTIONS) {
		localStorage.setItem('mostRecentScore', score);

		return window.location.assign('/minecraft/end');
	}

	questionCounter++;
	progressText.innerText = `Question ${questionCounter} of ${MAX_QUESTIONS}`;
	progressBarFull.style.width = `${(questionCounter / MAX_QUESTIONS) * 100}%`;

	const questionsIndex = Math.floor(
		Math.random() * availableQuestions.length
	);
	currentQuestion = availableQuestions[questionsIndex];
	question.innerText = currentQuestion.question;

	choices.forEach((choice) => {
		const number = choice.dataset['number'];
		choice.innerText = currentQuestion['choice' + number];
	});

	availableQuestions.splice(questionsIndex, 1);

	acceptingAnswers = true;
};

choices.forEach((choice) => {
	choice.addEventListener('click', (e) => {
		if (!acceptingAnswers) return;

		acceptingAnswers = false;
		const selectedChoice = e.target;
		const selectedAnswer = selectedChoice.dataset['number'];

		let classToApply =
			selectedAnswer == currentQuestion.answer ? 'correct' : 'incorrect';

		if (classToApply === 'correct') {
			incrementScore(SCORE_POINTS);
		}

		if (classToApply === 'incorrect') {
			decrementScore(SCORE_POINTS);
		}

		selectedChoice.parentElement.classList.add(classToApply);

		setTimeout(() => {
			selectedChoice.parentElement.classList.remove(classToApply);
			getNewQuestion();
		}, 1000);
	});
});

incrementScore = (num) => {
	score += num;
	scoreText.innerText = score;
};

// function to deduct 100 points for wrong answer
decrementScore = (num) => {
	score -= num;
	scoreText.innerText = score;
};

startGame();
